reachppc.com 2012-01-20

# ReachPPC.com Pay Per Click Advertising Solution Provider

## Effective July 12, 2010

Your privacy is important to **ReachPPC, Inc., an Epic Media Group company** , so we have created the following Privacy Policy to let you know what information we collect when you visit our websites and websites in our advertising network when we serve advertisements on our network of websites (collectively, the "ReachPPC Network"), why we collect it and how it is used. ReachPPC is a member of the [ReachJunction Media Limited](http://www.reachjunction.com/).

The terms "you," "your," and "yours" refer to the web surfer and/or consumer utilizing our Network. The terms "ReachPPC," "we," "us," and "our" refer to ReachPPC, Inc. and its partners.

Please read this privacy policy carefully. Use of the ReachPPC Network and your sharing of information with the ReachPPC Network is subject to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and the website's Terms and Conditions.

## I. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

The ReachPPC Network contains more than 1,000 websites to which we deliver advertisements and which you, the web surfer, may occasionally visit. During your visit to the ReachPPC Network, ReachPPC and/or our third party vendors may collect certain information, as follows.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

"Personally Identifiable Information" or "PII" means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including first and last name, physical address, email address, or telephone number.

To access certain websites operated by ReachPPC in the ReachPPC Network, we may ask you to register and provide certain PII. ReachPPC is committed to making sure that you have clear notice and choice before sharing any PII. Web surfers who have provided PII may elect to have their data deleted from our files, or kept from being used for purposes other than for the requested service, by following the procedures set forth below in the "Access" section below.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

ReachPPC also automatically receives and records anonymous information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website which is part of the ReachPPC Network. We use log files to collect Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser, and responses by a web surfer to an advertisement delivered by us. This information may be stored on our systems for about one year.

ReachPPC uses technology, including technology from its third party advertising vendors, which includes cookies, "web beacons" and/or "action tags." A "cookie" is a small text file stored by your browser on your computer when you visit our Network. A "web beacon" or "action tag" is a small image (usually 1x1 pixel) embedded in a web page or email. We use cookies, web beacons and action tags to collect non-personally identifiable data to provide better and more relevant services and messages to that user. Cookies, web beacons and action tags permit us to recognize users and avoid repetitive requests for the same information.

As a rule, non-personally identifiable information is anonymous and is not used to identify a specific person by ReachPPC.

Web surfers may elect not to provide non-personally identifiable information by following the cookie opt-out procedures set forth below. 

## II. HOW IS SUCH INFORMATION USED?

**Personally identifiable information**

We collect PII from customers who are individuals or companies that wish to enter into business relationships with ReachPPC, including websites and marketers. This customer information is used only for purposes of administering these relationships, including maintaining account information and managing payments. In addition, our lead generation business may gather personally identifiable information.

ReachPPC will not disclose personal information unless required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) comply with the law or legal process served on ReachPPC; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of ReachPPC; or (3) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of ReachPPC, its websites or the public. If ReachPPC should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, we may sell the information you provide to us to a third party or share the information with any company with whom we merge or that acquires all or substantially all of our stock or assets. 

**Non-personally identifiable information**

ReachPPC will use your non-personal information in order to better target advertisements across the ReachPPC Network, to provide aggregate reporting to advertisers and clients, and to improve our advertising systems and products. We use the information to analyze site usage, administer the site, understand usage and navigation trends in aggregate, and determine the relevance of content. We may also share non-personally identifiable information with our subsidiaries and third party partners for similar use.

## III. ACCESS TO PII

ReachPPC allows visitors to the ReachPPC Network who have provided PII to access, correct, amend or delete any PII they have provided by sending us a letter at the contact listed below.

## IV. SECURITY

ReachPPC employs commercially reasonable security measures to ensure the security of all data. In addition, we comply with all applicable data security laws. Although no system is full proof, in the event of a breach we will comply with all applicable notification requirements required under the law.

## V. CHOICE AND OPT-OUT

**Non-personally identifiable information**

ReachPPC is a member of the [ReachJunction Media Limited](http://www.reachjunction.com/) and works with industry leading companies to address important privacy and consumer protection issues in online advertising. ReachPPC's information usage practices are based on two beliefs: first, that protecting user privacy is essential to the growth and prosperity of the Internet; second, that a personalized web experience can provide significant benefits to Internet end users if done properly. In accordance with these beliefs, ReachPPC creates value for consumers, advertisers and publishers in revolutionary ways without compromising individual privacy.

If you prefer not to receive targeted advertisements delivered by ReachPPC you can opt-out of our program. Please note that if you opt-out, ReachPPC will continue to collect non-personal information in connection with ad serving for limited reporting and auditing purposes. Examples of these include but are not limited to reporting overall advertising performance, geographic activity, and other similar analyses. Most browsers will accept cookies unless you change your browser settings to refuse them and opt-out of the use of ReachPPC cookies and those of our third party advertising technology vendors. For more information on cookies and how to manage and delete them, please visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

## VI. CHILDREN'S PRIVACY AND SPAM

ReachPPC is very sensitive to the issue of children's privacy and makes every effort to protect the privacy of children using the Internet. ReachPPC's web site, products, and services are not developed for or directed at children under 13. For that reason, ReachPPC does not knowingly collect or maintain PII or non-personally identifiable information on the ReachPPC websites from persons under 13 years of age. Any person who provides their information to ReachPPC through the login page for new customers or website users or any other part of the ReachPPC Network represents to ReachPPC that they are 13 years of age or older. If ReachPPC learns that PII of persons under 13 years of age has been collected on the ReachPPC websites we will take appropriate steps to delete this information. 

ReachPPC is committed to proper Internet practices and full compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. 

## VII. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS AND SAFE HARBOR

Personal information collected on the ReachPPC Network and websites may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which ReachPPC or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this website you acknowledge and agree that we may transfer your personal information outside of the country in which you live and that you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. ReachPPC adheres to the Safe Harbor Agreement concerning the transfer of personal data from the EU to the United States. In order to comply with the European Union's Safe Harbor principles, we commit to resolve any complaints by European Union citizens relating to this policy, which cannot be resolved directly with our company, through the Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.'s Safe Harbor Privacy Dispute Resolution Procedure. 

## VII. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

ReachPPC may find it necessary or be legally obligated to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post those changes on this page and update the effective date so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. For changes to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of the personal information you have already provided to us, we will attempt to obtain your consent before implementing such revisions with respect to such information, or notify you either by placing a prominent notice on the home page of our web site or by directly sending you a notification. For all other changes, it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy frequently and remain informed about any changes to it, so we encourage you to visit this page often. Your continued use of the ReachPPC Network constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.

## VIII. CONTACT US

For more information or if you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please send correspondence to the following address: ReachPPC, Privacy Officer, 2141 Rosecrans Ave., Suite 2020, El Segundo, CA 90245 or at [support@reachppc.com](mailto:support@reachppc.com).
